♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
‪["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
[Olga] But you know,
in fairness to Ibyang,
she's such a sweet and thoughtful child.
Whoever her parents are,
they're very lucky.
I think it's time
you give the child back to us.
Why? Are you returning her
to her real mother?
[in English] That's none of your concern.
[Mayor's wife] They picked up a man.
They say he's good at fighting.
- [in English] You will…
- [grunts]
[in English] You're not going to say
where the laptop is.
[in English] Right now, I'm searching
for all of your beloved.
[in English] And I will kill every
one of them right in front of your face.
[in English] Mission status.
[in English] Outside the establishment.
[in English] Potential headquarters
of Anthony "Atoy" Padua.
[Samir, in English]
Is she important to you?
[in English] Does she matter to you?
[Atoy, in English] No, no, no! Stop! Stop!
[in English] I'm the only one
who can access it,
and I can erase every classified info
you have on there.
[in English] Plan didn't work out, huh?
[cackles]
[groans]
[moans]
PREVIOUSLY
So, if you want to live longer,
learn to listen to me.
- [Red, in English] You understand? Huh?
- [moaning]
[Janine] Uncle Red locked me and Mommy up.
What did you do to Audrey,
to my granddaughter?!
[Red] She's not really your granddaughter.
She's not really Audrey's daughter either.
You're truly worthless.
[grunts and groans]
[Red] She was going to report us
to the police!
I just stopped her!
[Atoy] You think you're tough
for beating up a tied-up man?
[Samir, in English] Stand up
and let us fight.
[Atoy grunts]
[music fades]
[rousing music playing]
[gasps]
[gun cocks]
[music fades]
[in English] Kill me now. Huh?
[in English] Kill me now!
[in English] What, huh?!
This is what you want, isn't it?!
This will make you happy, won't it?!
[in English] Kill me now!
- [grunts]
- [in English] Do it!
- [growls]
[tense music playing]
[heavy breathing]
[in English] You're not worth it.
[in English] You're not… worth it.
‪[heavy breathing]
[in English, softly] Not worth it?
You're the one who will die!
[Red grunts]
[groans]
Find him.
When you see him, shoot him.
Boss, are you sure? He's your father.
- It's none of your business! Hurry up!
- [thug] Yes.
[suave theme music playing]
[music fades]
- [Gavin] Janine? Janine!
- [car door clicks shut]
- Brother Gavin! [sobs]
- [Gavin] Why are you crying?
- [in English] What's wrong?
- They're--
Grandpa and Uncle Red are fighting!
Uncle Red is bad.
He locked me and Mommy up!
- [in English] What?
- [sobs]
Huh?
- [gunfire blasting in the distance]
- [gasping]
[tense music playing]
- [music fades]
- [panting and groaning]
[in English] Dad!
[somber music playing]
[stammers, in English] Dad!
- [gasping]
- [groaning]
What happened, Dad, huh?
- Who-- Who did this to you?
- [groans]
It was Red. Red did this to me.
- He's ruthless.
- [groans]
You need to be taken to the hospital.
- [grunts]
- [shrieks]
[in English] Dad! Dad! Dad!
‪[groans]
Run away.
- Audrey, run away!
- [in English] No!
[in English] I'm not leaving
you and my daughter, Dad!
[in English] No, no!
- [sobs]
- [groans]
[in English] No, Dad.
Forgive me, my child,
if I didn't tell you the truth.
And I'm sorry you grew up
in this kind of life.
[in English] I'm sorry.
Dad, that doesn't matter now. [sobs]
[in English] We have to get out of here.
Stand up, Dad. Get up.
- Please, get up!
- [groans]
[sobs]
We can still escape!
[in English] Dad, come on!
I just have to find Janine!
I already helped her escape.
But there's something
you need to know about Janine.
[heavy breathing]
She's not really your daughter.
[music fades]
[pensive music playing]
[pants, in English] No. That's…
[in English] Tha-Th-That's impossible,
Dad.
Red and Martina… They lied about Janine.
They deceived us.
They deceived us. [groans]
[in English] We'll-- We'll--
We'll figure it out later, Dad.
We need to get out of here.
- Please try!
- [groans]
- [in English] Help me. Please try, Dad.
[in English] Dad!
[music fades]
[metal clanging in the distance]
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Let's go, coward.
[in English] I'll let you hit me first.
[in English] You need this one. Okay?
Boss. Boss is going to fight.
Boss, you can do it.
You can do it, boss!
[in English] Resting for focus. Focus!
[in English] I'm right here!
[grunts]
- [thug mutters]
- [in English] Okay…
Boss, you can do it, boss!
[in English] I see. You're ready, huh.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[chuckles]
[grunting and groaning]
[grunts]
[in English] Let's do this!
[Samir, in English] Okay.
[in English] Okay.
[grunting and groaning]
[music fades]
[tense music playing]
[groans]
[grunting and groaning]
- [ominous music playing]
- [buzzing]
[groaning]
[Lily sobbing]
[in English] Get the cutter.
[Lily, in English] No, no, no, no.
[in English] No, no, no, no, no!
[in English] No! Brother, don't.
Brother, brother, don't, don't, brother!
- [sobs] Don't!
- [Atoy] You're unfair!
But I won't back down. What, round two?!
- [Lily] Don't!
- [Atoy] What's that?
Hey! Don't, don't, don't, don't,
don't, don't!
- Don't, don't!
- [Lily screams]
- [guttural cry of pain]
- [buzzing]
You demons!
[bawling]
- [Lily screaming]
- [guttural cry of pain]
[heavy breathing]
Mmm, there. Let me see.
Ah, that looks good!
Ma, where are we going?
Just nearby.
Can we take a picture first?
Oh, sure.
[somber music playing]
[camera shutter snaps]
- One more.
- Ah, one more.
[camera shutter snaps]
- Ma.
- Mmm?
Is it okay if you go to school?
[melancholic music playing]
Because Tatoy might not be there yet.
Um… Why… Why is that?
What's happening?
Because our moving-up ceremony is near.
I'm the top student,
and they said there's a medal!
Wow.
Um, can you be the one to put it on me?
Really?
Yes!
And next year, I'll do even better!
And I'll join all the contests!
So you'll always be on stage.
Oh, no!
I might get tired of going up the stage
to put medals on you.
But that's what I want.
And I also want my classmates to see you.
Hmm? Why?
So I can say I'm no longer adopted,
and I already have a mom.
[music fades]
[sentimental music playing]
Dad, hold on. Please, I beg you.
- [groans]
- [sobs]
[in English] Dad, please.
[suspenseful music playing]
- [in English] Wow!
- [gasps]
So, this is a family reunion, huh?
[grunts]
Don't come near!
You animal! [grunts]
[Dmitri, in English] No, Audrey.
[Dmitri] Run away!
- [in English] I'm not leaving you here!
- [groans]
No. Let us go, Red.
Do you think I'd be scared of your gun?
Do you know how many times
I've had a gun pointed at me?
[in English] That's right.
I forgot you're evil!
[Audrey sobs]
Aside from what you did to our dad…
[inhales] You weren't content with that,
you also took my child away!
[tense music playing]
You even made me believe Janine
was really my daughter!
So, you already know, huh?
You were happy,
even if your child was fake, right?
Your life had purpose.
[sobs] Where is my real child?!
[Audrey sobs]
Who is she?!
- [music swells]
- [clicks tongue]
I'll never tell you, even if you shoot me.
[gasping]
[growls]
[Audrey, in English] You're a monster!
[sobbing]
[tense music playing]
[in English] A monster?
Don't blame me, blame him!
Blame him!
Red…
Stop it, please.
[Red] Stop what? Stop what, huh?!
- [Dmitri] Stop it.
- I put up with this for so long!
I'm just starting,
and now you're telling me to stop?!
When Mom died, huh!
You think you're the only one
who lost her?!
who got hurt?!
I was hurt too!
I lost someone too!
But why do you blame me, huh?!
Oh, and you, you!
Why didn't you go with her, huh?!
Why did you leave her?!
[in English] She was worried about you,
that's why she had the accident!
Mom died because of you!
- How dare you blame it on someone else!
- [in English] Oh… Shut up!
Whatever you are now, you chose that!
Didn't it ever occur to you, huh?!
I struggled to move on, didn't I?!
That's why I became like this!
[ominous music playing]
My whole life,
you all blamed me, didn't you?!
Maybe if you just showed me a little love!
Just a little!
Maybe I wouldn't have grown up
like this, right?!
Damn near everything!
Everything you wanted me to do, I did!
Even bad things!
I did them to please you!
[in English] Yes, you're right!
[in English] I am a monster.
[in English] But he created me!
[music fades]
- [groans, grunts]
- [in English] Dad. Dad!
[Dmitri] Stop it, Red!
- [Dmitri] Stop it! Run away!
- [in English] No, Dad!
- [in English] Dad!
- [in English] Run away!
[in English] No!
- [both grunt, shouting]
- [gunshots]
[in English] Dad!
[Dmitri groans]
[sobbing]
- [wailing]
- [grunts]
[groans]
[wailing]
Auntie!
- Janine!
- Mommy!
[wails]
Auntie, what happened?
Gavin… [sobs]
Gavin, Red shot your grandfather!
[in English] What? Why?
We need to get out of here
because he wants to kill us too!
Get in here.
Ma'am, what happened, ma'am?
Run, run away!
- You might get dragged into this!
- [Gavin] Please open the gate!
[Audrey] My brother is out of his mind!
Put on your seat belt, child!
Faster, Gavin!
[in English] Go! Go!
[music fades]
How did we end up like this?
[pensive music playing]
Father and son killing each other.
[in English] You know, Dad…
I worshipped you.
I loved you so much.
You know, at one point,
I felt that you loved me too.
[Dmitri, in English] Red, you fold it
this way, like this.
[in English] And then, the wings!
Last part, the wings.
That's the wings, okay.
Like this, those are the wings. Okay.
[in English] Okay!
[in English] Now, it's ready to fly!
What? Let's do it together, huh!
- Yes.
- [in English] Okay.
Here it is. Together?
You first, Dad!
[in English] Oh, okay. Watch.
[pensive music playing]
See? Did you see that?
It flew well, right? Now it's your turn.
- Okay. That's ready now.
- [in English] Okay.
[in English] For sure.
[in English] One, two, three!
[screams, in English] I hate this!
I've made so many!
[in English] It doesn't fly!
[screams] I always make mistakes!
[in English] Hey. Son, relax. Sit down.
[in English] It's okay.
It's okay. No matter
how many mistakes you make.
Just make another one.
I don't count how many mistakes you have.
It can be 100 or more than 100,
that's fine with me!
[in English] It's okay. Okay?
[in English] All you have to do
is make another one.
[in English] Okay?
- [in English] Okay?
- [in English] Okay, Dad.
Let's make another one, huh.
[in English] Okay, here.
[in English] That's your paper
and this is my paper. Okay.
[pensive music playing]
You said you wouldn't count
my mistakes, right?
[in English] I remember that.
You said, even if reaches 100 or more,
you wouldn't count them.
[sharp inhale]
When did you start counting?
[heavy breathing]
I can't remember.
[sobbing]
When Mommy died…
[sobs]
I didn't feel like I was your son anymore.
[sobbing]
It seemed like it was so hard
for you to love me.
[sobs] Dad…
Did it ever occur to you?
I wouldn't have become like this
if you hadn't deprived me of love.
[sobs]
[in English] You think I wanted this?
[sobbing]
You deprived me!
- [sobs]
- [heavy breathing]
[in English] I'm… I'm sorry, my son.
[gasps]
[in English] I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
[in English] I'm sorry. [sobs]
[in English] I'm sorry!
[in English] I'm sorry, my son.
[in English] It's just not enough.
[gunshot]
[epic music playing]
[exhales]
[music fades]
[Atoy] Sorry, Lily.
We won't be able to get out anymore.
We'll rot here.
Why are you saying that?
I can't stay here, Atoy.
My child still needs me.
I need to live.
I thought you were going to save me.
Save you?
Why would I save you?
Why, huh?
Are you a good person?
You're in cahoots with them, aren't you?
You work for them.
You knew that the information you have
is very important to national security.
[pensive music playing]
You're involved in this, right?
You knew they were training.
What's their purpose?
They're terrorists.
They won't do anything
but kill millions of Filipinos.
And now, you want me to save you? [huffs]
I regret it now, Atoy.
I just wanted to work for my child.
And to extend the lives of my parents too.
I'm the only one they rely on.
[scoffs]
It's too late for regrets.
We'll rot here.
You're all the same.
[Lily sighs]
Atoy.
Everyone makes wrong decisions
that can be corrected.
I can't blame you
if you don't want to save me
because of my job.
Just think, I also have a family.
Think of the people who love you.
I don't believe you don't have a family.
I know you only said that to Samir
so no one else would get dragged in.
[melodramatic music playing]
Do you know that he won't file
a case against you
because he's thinking about Janine and me?
We are a family.
You, me, Janine.
We are a family!
That's what matters most.
We-- We are a family!
But how can I tell our child
that you almost killed her grandfather?!
Janine, my child?
Did Dad hurt Grandpa?
- [Janine] Huh?
- [Audrey] Child.
- [Audrey] Let's go, child.
- [Atoy] Child, no.
- [Audrey, in English] Please.
- Janine.
[music swells]
[Atoy] I treated you like family!
I've long wanted to tell you everything,
but Delfin told me to keep it from you.
[Atoy] What secret? Don't-- Don't--
Don't use Dad to justify
what you did, Godmother!
Forgive me, forgive me.
Blame me, not Karla.
I just didn't want to ruin what we had.
I didn't want to hurt you, Atoy.
Atoy, forgive me.
[Atoy] You're unbelievable.
Unbelievable!
[Cita] Atoy. [sobbing]
- I don't need you.
- [Cita] Atoy.
[sobbing]
[mouthing] You too.
[Ibyang] Thank you, Tatoy.
If not for you… [sobs]
I wouldn't have a family.
No one can replace you
because I love you.
[Atoy] Because of you,
I got to know myself better.
That's why I love you so much, Ibyang.
[Ibyang sobbing]
[Atoy] I'll miss you.
[epic music playing]
What I said is true.
[sharp inhale]
I have no family anymore.
No one cares about me now.
My life has no meaning anymore.
[music swells]
[henchman] Here.
Your food!
Eat it yourself.
[pensive music playing]
[grunts]
[groans]
What?
Is that all you can do, huh?!
Go ahead! Kick me again!
You're nothing!
Eat that! Kick me again if you want!
Do whatever you want! Go on!
- [henchman] Ah, is that so?
- Go on!
[grunts and groans] Go on!
[Lily] Stop it!
What? What, are you done?!
Go on!
Kill me now,
so I can join my mother and father!
[Lily] Atoy!
[groans]
Don't cause any more trouble.
Why are you doing this to yourself?
Have mercy.
[music fades]
[exhales]
You know, I feel you're a good person
because you risked your life to…
to save me.
[pensive music playing]
That was just work.
I could die here so it would all be over.
Don't say that.
You shouldn't give up.
Because you're still important
to other people.
Even if you say you don't have a family.
Surely, you left a mark
on at least one person.
"Tatoy, Tatoy,
thank you for your love.
Every day, I always feel it.
Because of you, my life is so happy."
Come here. Thank you.
- [melodramatic music playing]
- [Ibyang] Mmm.
[soft moan]
Audrey escaped, and that child
is the only way to bring Audrey back here.
She won't speak.
Just think about what Atoy would do
if he found out that Ibyang
is really his true child.
Ibyang is Atoy's child?
What did you hear?
I'll tell Atoy everything.
UP NEXT
- [in English] Not so fast.
- [shrieks]
- Is Uno there?
- He's inside. Why?
I think he's a spy.
[Karla] Maybe he's working
for Red Regalia.
- Caught you!
- [Karla] I knew it.
- My suspicion was right!
- [grunts]
[grunts and groans]
Boss, what if Audrey
went to another police station?
There's only one person they'll go to.
[Charmi] Don't do anything bad.
[in English] Don't tell me
that you don't know them.
If I find out you hurt them…
I'll stitch you to the wall,
and feed you to animals like you.
[in English] Good luck with that.
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias